Guide to the John Hay Whitney and Betsey Cushing Whitney Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- John Hay Whitney and Betsey Cushing Whitney, 1849-2008; Series I
  - Topical
    - Financial files
      - Companies
        - Beckhampton Limited
          - Balance sheets, 1982-1984 (Box 100, Folder 2)
          - Directors' meeting minutes, 1969-1976 (Box 100, Folder 3)
          - Investments, business loans from John Hay Whitney, 1970-1982 (Box 100, Folder 4)
          - Ledgers
            - 1969 (Box 100, Folder 5)
            - 1969-1982 (oversize) (Box 391, Folder 1)
          - United States Corporation tax forms, New York state tax forms
            Includes excerpts from corporate ledgers that provide context for the company's financial interests and dealings.
            - 1970-1978 (Box 101, Folder 1-9)
            - 1979-1983 (Box 102, Folder 1-5)
        - Classic Partners, investment in, 1975-1977 (Box 103, Folder 1)
        - Corinthian Broadcasting Corporation
          - General, 1967-1970, 1967-1977 (Box 103, Folder 2)
          - Public offering bound volume (oversize), 1967 (Box 391, Folder 2)
        - Dun & Bradstreet
          - Common stocks, share of, 1979-1981 (Box 103, Folder 3-4)
          - Corinthian Broadcasting Company, sale of, 1967 (Box 103, Folder 5)
          - Sale of shares, 1974-1976 (Box 103, Folder 6)
          - Stock transfers, 1972-1974 (Box 103, Folder 7)
        - Film Classics, Incorporated, 1943, 1949-1951 (Box 104, Folder 1)
        - Freeport Sulphur Company, 1953-1964 (Box 104, Folder 2)
        - Geovision, Incorporated
          - Correspondence, 1954-1974 (Box 104, Folder 3)
          - Bylaws, certificates of incorporation, 1946, 1954-1956, 1975-1976 (Box 104, Folder 4)
        - Greenstreet Company
          - Accounting, balance sheets, 1982-1983 (Box 104, Folder 5)
          - Agreement concerning death of a general partner, 1975 (Box 104, Folder 6)
          - Auditors
            - Arthur Anderson and Company, 1983 (Box 104, Folder 7)
            - Taxes, correspondence and returns
              - 1972-1975 (Box 104, Folder 8)
              - 1978-1981 (Box 104a, Folder 1-5)
              - 1982-1984 (Box 104b, Folder 1-4)
          - Correspondence
            - General, 1969-1980 (Box 105, Folder 1)
            - Contribution of capital by partners, 1968-1978 (Box 105, Folder 2)
          - Crossville Rubber Products, Incorporated
            - General, 1982-1983 (Box 105, Folder 3-4)
            - 12% Senior note, 1978, 1983 (Box 105, Folder 5)
          - Financial statements, 1976-1982 (Box 105, Folder 6)
          - Hamilton Brothers Oil Company
            - 1980-1987 (Box 105, Folder 7-8)
            - 1981-1987 (Box 106, Folder 1)
          - Idaho Company limited partnership
            - General, 1971-1972, 1976-1984 (Box 106, Folder 2)
            - Assignment by the Idaho Company, 1972 (Box 106, Folder 3)
            - Correspondence, 1971-1979 (Box 106, Folder 4)
            - Payments, 1970-1972 (Box 106, Folder 5)
          - Ledgers
            - 1968-1982 (oversize) (Box 391, Folder 3)
            - 1975-1982 (Box 106, Folder 6)
          - Liquidation, correspondence, 1983 (Box 106, Folder 7)
          - Litchstreet Company, Idaho Company investment
            - General information, background, 1977-1978, 1981-1990 (Box 107, Folder 1-6)
            - Idaho Company investment, 1977-1984 (Box 107, Folder 7)
            - Limited partnership agreement amendment, 1978 (Box 108, Folder 1)
            - Loans and demand notes, 1980, 1982 (Box 108, Folder 2)
            - Partnership returns, 1975 (Box 108, Folder 3-4)
          - Partnership agreements, 1968-1984 (Box 108, Folder 5-6)
          - Securities and Exchange Commission registration, 1977 (Box 108, Folder 7)
          - Security cards, 1978-1982 (Box 108, Folder 8)
          - Swamp Company
            - Accounting files, 1979-1981 (Box 109, Folder 1)
            - Correspondence, 1979-1983 (Box 109, Folder 2)
            - Ledger (oversize), 1979-1982 (Box 392, Folder 1)
            - Limited partnership agreement, 1979 (Box 109, Folder 3)
            - United States Partnership, return of income, 1979-1983 (Box 109, Folder 4-6)
          - United States Trust Company
            - General, 1968-1990 (Box 109, Folder 7-9)
            - Financial statements, 1979-1983 (Box 110, Folder 1)
            - Payments, 1969-1983 (Box 110, Folder 2)
          - Whitney, John Hay investment in Greenstreet Company, 1968-1980 (Box 110, Folder 3)
          - Work papers, 1980-1984 (Box 110, Folder 4-5)
        - Greenwood Fund, 1958-1973 (Box 111, Folder 1)
          Provided training fellowships to secondary school teachers in the humanities and sciences. Includes trustees' meeting minutes, bylaws, and articles of incorporation and dissolution.
        - Greenwood Seed Company
          - Tax returns, federal and state, 1978-1984 (Box 111, Folder 2)
          - United States Corporation income tax return, 1981-1982, 1984 (Box 111, Folder 3-4)
        - Internal Instruments-Geovision, 1948-1951 (Box 111, Folder 5)
        - Investment and business loans, 1933-1981 (Box 111, Folder 6-7)
        - Javits Book Group, investment, 1978-1980 (Box 111, Folder 8)
        - J. H. Whitney & Company
          - 50th Anniversary plaque, 1996 (Box 112, Folder 1)
          - 1990 Equity Fund
            - General, 1990-1995 (Box 112, Folder 2)
            - Cash calls, 1993-1995 (Box 112, Folder 3)
            - Financial statements, 1993-1998 (Box 113, Folder 1-4)
            - Limited Partnership
              - General, 1995-1997 (Box 113, Folder 5-7)
              - Distributions, 1993-1995 (Box 114, Folder 1)
            - Subordinated debt fund
              - General, 1990-1999 (Box 114, Folder 2-9)
              - Cash calls, 1993-1995 (Box 114, Folder 10)
              - Financials, 1993-1995 (Box 115, Folder 1-2)
              - Partnership distribution, 1994-1995 (Box 115, Folder 3)
          - Correspondence, 1948-1951, 1956-1994 (Box 116, Folder 1-4)
          - Distribution from J. H. Whitney & Company to John Hay Whitney Estate, 1982-1985 (Box 116, Folder 5-6)
          - Federal Communications Commission appointments, 1958 (Box 116, Folder 7)
          - Firm overview, history, Circa 1950 (Box 116, Folder 8)
          - Life Story Magazine press, 1948, 1950-1957 (Box 116, Folder 9-10)
          - Luncheon schedules
            - 1949-1952 (Box 117, Folder 1-4)
            - 1953-1954 (Box 118, Folder 1-2)
          - News clippings, Circa 1980-1990 (Box 119, Folder 1)
          - The Potentialities and Pitfalls of Financing Small Enterprises (by Whitney), 1958 December 2 (Box 119, Folder 2)
          - Vitarine settlement agreement, write-off, 1992-1993 (Box 119, Folder 3)
          - Withdrawal of television stocks, Venezolano, 1959 (Box 119, Folder 4)
        - Media stocks, 1957-1967 (Box 119, Folder 5)
        - New York Airways, Incorporated
          - Directors' meetings, correspondence, 1975-1982 (Box 120, Folder 1-2)
          - Financing, 1973 (Box 120, Folder 3)
          - Loan guarantee, 1974 (Box 120, Folder 4)
          - Recapitalization agreement, 1973 (Box 120, Folder 5)
        - New York City Basis, 1952-1969 (Box 120, Folder 6)
        - Pioneer Pictures, Incorporated
          - Assignment of copyrights, 1937-1943 (Box 121, Folder 1-2)
          - Correspondence
            - General, 1932-1943, 1959-1984 (Box 121, Folder 3-8)
            - Cooper, Merian, 1934-1935 (Box 122, Folder 1)
            - Story properties, 1948-1951 (Box 122, Folder 2)
          - Contracts, 1935-1937 (Box 122, Folder 3)
          - Films
            Documents the production and postproduction of films produced by Pioneer Pictures, Incorporated, during the 1930s and 1940s.
            - General files, 1933-1953, 1981-1983, 1995 (Box 122, Folder 4)
              Includes storage lists and documentation of materials sent to the Harry Ransom Center, University of Texas, during the 1990s.
            - A Star is Born, 1937 (Box 122, Folder 5-6)
            - Gone with the Wind
              - Contracts, 1942 (Box 123, Folder 1)
              - New York premiere, 1939 (Box 123, Folder 2)
                Includes correspondence about the use of African-American images in publicity material.
              - Prints inventory, 1942 (Box 123, Folder 3)
              - Sale, 1943 (Box 123, Folder 4)
            - La Cucaracha, 1934-1936 (Box 123, Folder 5)
            - Rebecca
              - General, 1938-1943, 1966-1967 (Box 123, Folder 6)
              - Correspondence, 1942-1944 (Box 123, Folder 7)
          - Film inventory, storage, 1965, 1979, 1981 (Box 124, Folder 1)
          - Financial reports, 1934-1940 (Box 124, Folder 2)
          - Incorporation, 1934 (Box 124, Folder 3)
            Includes correspondence between Whitney and several other executives about film color processing.
          - Liquidation, 1940 (Box 124, Folder 4)
          - Party agreements, 1935-1939 (Box 124, Folder 5)
          - Reorganization, 1940 (Box 124, Folder 6)
          - Spectrum Corporation
            - General, 1936-1937 (Box 124, Folder 7)
            - Dissolution, 1933-1942 (Box 124, Folder 8)
        - Publications Research, Incorporated, 1939-1942 (Box 125, Folder 1-2)
          Contains contracts, stockholders' meeting minutes, and liquidation paperwork.
        - Sanoderm Company, Incorporated, 1938, 1943 (Box 125, Folder 3)
        - Whitcom Investment Company
          - Correspondence, 1968-1980 (Box 125, Folder 4)
          - Limited partnership agreements, 1976, 1978 (Box 125, Folder 5)
          - Whitney, John Hay, investment in, 1967-1980 (Box 125, Folder 6)
        - Whitgreen Limited
          - General
            - 1970-1988 (Box 126, Folder 1-2)
            - 1977-1996 (Box 127, Folder 1-7)
            - 1985-1997 (Box 128, Folder 1-6)
            - 1997-1998 (Box 129, Folder 1-6)
          - Accounting, 1969-1970, 1988-1995 (Box 129, Folder 7-9)
          - Contribution of capital, 1988-1995 (Box 130, Folder 1-2)
          - Land registry, 1970 (Box 130, Folder 3)
          - Tax reports, 1969-1976 (Box 130, Folder 4-6)
          - United States Trust Company, correspondence, 1987-1995 (Box 131, Folder 1)
        - Whitney Communications Corporation
          - Associates, 1962-1968 (Box 131, Folder 2)
          - Correspondence, 1961-1981 (Box 131, Folder 3)
      - Theatrical investments
        Documents John Hay Whitney's investments in New York City theatrical productions. Includes correspondence, contracts, and financial statements from various production companies: Alcar Productions, Incorporated; Aldblack Productions, Incorporated; Almac Productions, Incorporated; Almad Productions, Incorporated; Alton Productions, Incorporated; Hay Plays, Incorporated; Jay Jay, Incorporated; Jay Jay II, Incorporated; Lorelei Productions, Incorporated; Petarco, Incorporated; Plays, Incorporated; Pike's Peak, Incorporated; Spectrum Corporation; Whitplay Corporation; and Wildcat Incorporated.
        - General, 1928-1963 (Box 131a, Folder 1-8)
        - Company and productions lists, 1950 (Box 132, Folder 1)
        - "Jumbo", 1942-1952, 1974 (Box 132, Folder 2)
        - Plays Incorporated, 1940-1943 (Box 132, Folder 3)
      - Whitney, Betsey Cushing, personal
        - Carter, Ledyard, and Milburn; Sherman and Sterling
          - General, 1939-1995 (Box 132, Folder 4-5)
            Includes tax and financial advice these law firms provided Betsey Cushing Whitney.
          - Index of work performed for the Whitneys, 2008 (Box 132, Folder 6)
        - Commercial rent tax, 1992-1999 (Box 132, Folder 7)
        - Irene Selznick Company productions
          - Bell, Book, and Candle, 1950-1951 (Box 132, Folder 8)
          - The Chalk Garden, 1955-1957 (Box 133, Folder 1)
          - Flight into Egypt, 1952 (Box 133, Folder 2)
          - The Innocents, 1950 (Box 133, Folder 3)
          - A Streetcar Named Desire, 1957 (Box 133, Folder 4)
        - Investments, 1961-1970, 1986 (Box 133, Folder 5)
      - Whitney, John Hay, personal
        - Clubs and associations, 1928-1978 (Box 133, Folder 6)
        - Declined investment offers, 1958, 1967, 1974-1979 (Box 133, Folder 7)
        - Estate, 1982 (Box 133, Folder 8)
        - Gifts, 1959-1997 (Box 133, Folder 9)
        - Horses, England, 1947-1965 (Box 133, Folder 10)
        - Investments and business loans
          - Classic Partners, 1975-1983 (Box 133, Folder 11)
          - Miscellaneous, 1975-1983 (Box 133, Folder 12)
        - Ledgers
          - General (oversize), 1927-1982 (Box 134, Folder 1-4)
          - Securities
            - Marketable securities, 1967-1976 (Box 133, Folder 13)
            - Marketable common stock, 1931-1981 (Box 133, Folder 14-15)
            - State and municipal bonds, 1938-1941 (Box 133, Folder 16-18)
            - Marketable preferred stock, 1949-1950 (Box 133, Folder 19)
            - Securities, not readily marketable, 1927-1981 (Box 133, Folder 20-21)
        - Legal, 1929-1932 (Box 135, Folder 1)
          Contains memorandum of sale of land in Loudoun County, Virginia, and copy of John Hay Whitney trust.
        - Loans
          - General, 1958-1982 (Box 135, Folder 2-3)
          - Cooper, Merian C., 1963-1973 (Box 135, Folder 4)
          - Dun and Bradstreet Companies, Incorporated, 1969-1975 (Box 135, Folder 5)
          - Personal, 1925-1978 (Box 135, Folder 6)
          - Refused requests, 1955-1970 (Box 135, Folder 7-8)
          - Secure demand notes, 1959-1982 (Box 136, Folder 1-2)
        - Oil payment, 1959 (Box 136, Folder 3)
        - Requests for contributions from John Hay Whitney, 1963-1982 (Box 136, Folder 4)
        - Security market, United States Treasury, 1978-1982 (Box 136, Folder 5)
        - United States Trust Company of New York account, 1969-1983 (Box 136, Folder 6)
    - New York Herald Tribune
      - Correspondence
        - General
          Includes confidential memoranda from President Eisenhower about Whitney's plans to take over the paper; reports about the paper's finances; and letters and material about the ownership transition and the search for an editor and chief executive officer.
          - 1956-1960 Mar (Box 137, Folder 1-10)
            Includes correspondence about John Hay Whitney's interest in investing in the New York Herald Tribune. Also includes discussion about the European office.
          - 1960 Apr-1966 May (Box 138, Folder 1-10)
            Includes discussions about the role of partisan newspapers in public discourse, information about the merger with Journal American, World Telegram, and the New York Herald Tribune, and the 1966 strike.
        - Advertising, 1961-1966 (Box 139, Folder 1)
        - Alsop, Joseph, 1961-1974 (Box 139, Folder 2)
        - American Association of Advertising Agencies, 1961 (Box 139, Folder 3)
        - American Newspaper Publishers Association, 1961-1963 (Box 139, Folder 4)
        - Art Directors Club award, 1966 (Box 139, Folder 5)
        - Bellows, James, 1962-1966 (Box 139, Folder 6)
        - Board of Directors, 1961-1966 (Box 139, Folder 7)
        - Book and author luncheons, 1965-1966 (Box 139, Folder 8)
        - Bureaus
          - Paris, 1958-1960 (Box 139, Folder 9)
          - Paris, personnel, 1960-1963 (Box 139, Folder 10)
          - Washington, 1961-1966 (Box 139, Folder 11)
        - Capote, Truman, 1966 (Box 139, Folder 12)
        - Carte de commerςant, 1959-1961 (Box 139, Folder 13)
        - Churchill, Winston, 1961-1965 (Box 139, Folder 14)
        - Columbia University, 1961-1965 (Box 139, Folder 15)
        - Congratulations on acquisition of the New York Herald Tribune, 1958 (Box 140, Folder 1-2)
        - Cook, Don, 1961-1966 (Box 140, Folder 3)
        - Crist, Judith, 1963-1965 (Box 140, Folder 4)
        - Crosby, John, 1962-1965 (Box 140, Folder 5)
        - Demise of the New York Herald Tribune, 1966 (Box 140, Folder 6-8)
        - Denson, John, 1962-1964 (Box 140, Folder 9)
        - Editorial luncheons, 1961-1966 (Box 140, Folder 10-11)
        - Editorial page, 1961-1965 (Box 141, Folder 1)
        - Eisenhower, Dwight D., 1961-1966 (Box 141, Folder 2)
        - Executive editors, 1961-1964 (Box 141, Folder 3)
        - Federal Bureau of Investigation, 1961-1966 (Box 141, Folder 4)
          Includes correspondence from J. Edgar Hoover about the content of the newspaper.
        - Fresh Air Fund, 1961-1967 (Box 141, Folder 5-6)
        - Gallup study, 1961-1964 (Box 141, Folder 7)
        - Graham, Philip, 1962-1963 (Box 141, Folder 8)
        - Guggenheim, Harry F., 1963-1965 (Box 141, Folder 9)
        - Harriman, Averell, 1963-1965 (Box 141, Folder 10)
        - Higgins, Marguerite, 1965-1966 (Box 141, Folder 11)
        - International Herald Tribune, 1967-1982 (Box 141, Folder 12)
        - International Herald Tribune, 75th Anniversary celebration, 1962 (Box 141, Folder 13)
        - Irita Van Doran awards, 1963-1969 (Box 141, Folder 14)
        - Israel, 1962-1964 (Box 141, Folder 15)
        - Johnson, Lyndon B., 1963-1964 (Box 142, Folder 1)
          Contains correspondence about John F. Kennedy's assassination.
        - Johnson, Lyndon B., endorsement by New York Herald Tribune, 1964 (Box 142, Folder 2-3)
          Contains letters from subscribers criticizing and supporting the newspaper's decision to endorse Johnson for President over Republican nominee Barry M. Goldwater.
        - Kennedy family, 1962-1964 (Box 142, Folder 4)
          Includes letters from Jacqueline Kennedy.
        - Kinter, Robert E., 1961-1966 (Box 142, Folder 5)
        - Labor
          - General, 1961-1966 (Box 142, Folder 6)
            Includes memorandum from the Publishers' Assocation, union publications, internal memorandum about the 1962 union negotiation, and general information about the New York Typographical Union.
          - 1962-1963 strike (Box 142, Folder 7-8)
            Includes telegrams from Whitney, letters from Mayor John V. Lindsay asking the Secretary of Labor to intervene, letters from Whitney to his employees about the strike, correspondence debating whether to cease publication of the newspaper, and relevent press clippings.
          - 1965 strike (Box 142, Folder 9)
          - 1966 strike, New York Herald Tribune closure (Box 143, Folder 1-2)
        - Library morgue, disposition of, 1966-1982 (Box 143, Folder 3)
        - Lindsay, John V., 1964-1966 (Box 143, Folder 4)
        - Lippmann, Walter, 1961-1964 (Box 143, Folder 5)
        - Lodge, Henry Cabot, 1961-1964 (Box 143, Folder 6)
        - London bureau, 1961-1966 (Box 143, Folder 7)
        - Manning, Robert, 1958-1966 (Box 143, Folder 8)
        - Marketing plans, 1963-1965 (Box 143, Folder 9)
        - McKinsey and Company, 1958-1961 (Box 143, Folder 10)
        - Merger, 1966 January-March (Box 143, Folder 11)
        - New York City in Crisis series, 1960-1965 (Box 143, Folder 12)
        - New York Herald Tribune European Edition, Washington Post partnership, 1965-1966 (Box 144, Folder 1-2)
        - New York Hospital, 1961-1965 (Box 144, Folder 3)
        - New York Standard, 1963 (Box 144, Folder 4)
        - New York Times, 1961-1965 (Box 144, Folder 5)
        - New York World's Fair Corporation, 1962-1965 (Box 144, Folder 6)
        - The New Yorker, Tom Wolfe, 1965 (Box 144, Folder 7)
          Includes material sent to John Hay Whitney from J. D. Salinger.
        - Nixon, Richard M., 1961-1963 (Box 144, Folder 8)
        - Personnel, 1961-1966 (Box 144, Folder 9-12)
        - Price, Raymond K., Jr., 1967-1977 (Box 145, Folder 1)
        - Reid family, 1964-1966 (Box 145, Folder 2)
        - Rockefeller, Nelson, 1961-1965 (Box 145, Folder 3)
        - Rodgers, Donald I., 1962 (Box 145, Folder 4)
        - Sargent, Dwight Emerson, 1964 (Box 145, Folder 5)
        - Selznick, David O., 1963-1965 (Box 145, Folder 6)
        - Sunday paper
          - General, 1963-1966 (Box 145, Folder 7)
          - Book week, 1963-1966 (Box 145, Folder 8)
          - Reader reaction to new Sunday paper
            - 1963 Sep-Oct 28 (Box 145, Folder 9-10)
            - 1963 Oct 29-1964 Feb, undated (Box 146, Folder 1-2)
        - Syndicate, 1963-1964 (Box 146, Folder 3-4)
        - Time, Incorporated, 1961 (Box 146, Folder 5)
        - Twenty-Five Year Club party, 1961-1965 (Box 146, Folder 6)
        - United Kingdom publishers, 1961-1966 (Box 146, Folder 7)
        - United Nations, 1961-1964 (Box 146, Folder 8)
        - United Soviet Social Republic, 1964 (Box 146, Folder 9)
        - Weeks, Willet, 1963-1965 (Box 146, Folder 10)
        - White House cancellation of New York Herald Tribune, 1962 (Box 146, Folder 11-12)
        - Wise, David, 1962-1965 (Box 146, Folder 13)
        - WPAT newscasts, 1963 (Box 146, Folder 14)
        - World Journal Tribune, 1967 (Box 146, Folder 15)
        - World Journal Tribune Incorporated, 1966 (Box 147, Folder 1)
        - World Youth Forum, 1961-1967 (Box 147, Folder 2-3)
        - Zuckerman, Solly, 1963-1964 (Box 147, Folder 4)
      - Topical
        - John Hay Whitney Journalism Award submissions, 1983 (Box 147, Folder 5)
        - Ledgers, 1926 (Box 148, Folder 1-2)
        - Meeting minutes, 1945-1957 (Box 392, Folder 2-3)
        - Reorganization, 1957-1958 (Box 149, Folder 1-3)
        - Stock ledger, 1860-1957 (Box 150, Folder 1)
        - Stockholders and Directors meeting minutes, 1914-1944 (Box 151, Folder 1-2)
        - Tribune Association/ New York Tribune minute books, 1849-1913 (Box 152, Folder 1-4)
          - Oversize, 1849 January 1 (Box 393, Folder 7)
        - Tribune Association, stock certificates
          - Volume 1, 1860-1878 (Box 153, Folder 1)
          - Volume 3, 1889-1955 (Box 154, Folder 1)
        - White House cancellation of New York Herald Tribune (scrapbook of clippings), 1962 (Box 155–156)
    - Philanthropy
      - Clubs and associations
        - Whitney, Betsey Cushing
          - General, 1982-1997 (Box 157, Folder 1-2)
          - Declined, 1959-1962 (Box 157, Folder 3)
        - Whitney, John Hay, 1927-1992
          - A-Br (Box 158, Folder 1-11)
          - Bu-Com (Box 159, Folder 1-14)
          - Cor-Ei (Box 160, Folder 1-12)
          - En-G (Box 161, Folder 1-12)
          - Gl-K (Box 162, Folder 1-17)
          - L-Lond (Box 163, Folder 1-11)
          - Long-Ma (Box 164, Folder 1-9)
          - N-Pu (Box 165, Folder 1-21)
          - Q-T miscellaneous (Box 166, Folder 1-13)
          - Ta-Y (Box 167, Folder 1-12)
      - Contributions
        - Whitney, Betsey Cushing
          - General, 1958-1960, 1971-1980 (Box 167, Folder 13)
          - Charitable (ledger, alphabetical with amounts), 1952-1998
            - A-R (Box 168, Folder 1-17)
            - S-Z (Box 169, Folder 1-6)
          - Correspondence, 1958-1964 (Box 169, Folder 7)
          - Deductible
            - 1961-1978 (Box 170, Folder 1-18)
            - 1979-1981 (Box 170a, Folder 1-4)
          - Political
            - General, 1951-1996 (Box 170a, Folder 5-7)
            - A-Z, 1951-1996 (Box 170a, Folder 8)
          - Refusals, 1959-1987 (Box 170a, Folder 9)
        - Whitney, John Hay
          - Charitable
            - A-Z (ledger, alphabetical with amounts), 1942-1982 (Box 171, Folder 1-24)
          - Political
            - A-Z (ledger, alphabetical with amounts), 1947-1981 (Box 172, Folder 1-4)
            - Chronological (mostly correspondence)
              - 1966-1977 (Box 172, Folder 5-17)
              - 1978-1982 (Box 173, Folder 1-4)
            - Topical
              - Republican Party, 1952-1958 (Box 173, Folder 5)
                Relates to his work on the Republican National Finance Committee; the Republican Finance Committee for New York State; and contributions to the 1952 Eisenhower presidential campaign.